Good evening, everyone. Welcome again to this
evening session on spiritual warfare.
If we could switch over to the slides.
I hope everyone had a good day and I
hope that as you have gone through the day, you have
been a little bit more aware of the attacks of the devil
and that as he has attacked you, you've been able to run to
Jesus and ask for his help. Amen.
Okay, well, we're going to get right into it this evening and just
want to ask you to bow your heads forward of prayer as I pray up
here. Let's pray.
Father in heaven, I thank you for bringing each and every one of us here.
I thank you for your blessing upon our day and I thank
you for your protection. Father, I ask that as we look
at this topic of spiritual warfare, please send
us your Holy Spirit. We pray that your Holy Spirit will fill
our hearts and that you will open our eyes,
open our ears, help us to be able to see the message that you're trying
to give to us. And I pray that you would convict our hearts
of any unconfessed sin and any open
doors. As we go through tonight's session, Father,
I pray that you will speak to our hearts and help us each individually
to be able to see any open doors that we have that
we need to confess that we may be keeping open so
that demons have access to our lives. And I pray, Father, that you
would shut those doors and that you will give
us freedom from the enemy. I pray that you would please
surround this place with your holy angels. I pray that your holy angels would drive
any evil spirits that are here trying to
disturb, trying to confuse, trying to deceive.
I pray, Father, that you would drive them out from this place. In the name
of Jesus, our Lord and Savior. I thank you, Father,
in Jesus name, Amen.
Okay, so yesterday we looked at how
demons are able to attack us and how are they able to attack us
through our thoughts.
Right. Why are they able to attack us
through the open doors that we have in our lives? And tonight
we're going to look at what are those open doors?
What are the types of open doors or the types of doors that we can
open to allow demons to take control of
our minds and then eventually take control of our bodies?
Okay, so we're going to look into.
I'm sorry, look, we're going to look into how we
can.
We're going to look into how we can close
these doors as well. Right. And so the importance of
closing the open doors in our lives. And what are those open doors,
that's basically what we're going to be looking at. Okay,
So I want to review just
briefly the diagram that we looked
at yesterday. And that is negative
thoughts, right? Where do negative thoughts come from?
The devil and his evil spirits, Right.
And how can they have access to our
lives? Open doors. Okay. And we'll have a look at some quotes around
that. And what kind of open doors? Well, that's what we're going to touch on
tonight. But how do I counteract those
open doors or how do I counteract the negative thoughts that the devil is
hitting our minds with every single day? I need to counteract
that with positive thoughts from God.
Right? The only way to neutralize these negative thoughts is
really to memorize scripture,
to read scripture, to put the word of God into our hearts,
right? And when we hide the word of God in our hearts through
memorization, through self Bible study, in our
devotion time, through teaching the Bible, through preaching,
through praying, through claiming Bible verses, then God
will neutralize the negative thoughts in our
minds, right? And many times when we find that
we can't overcome the negative thoughts in our minds that really take
control of our bodies, it is because we are not spending
enough time in the word of God. Right? It is the word of
God that's going to neutralize us. Now,
yesterday we talked about how possession will
be kind of an end result of, you know,
years and years of addiction, years and years of
receiving the negative thoughts in our minds,
in our hearts. But the other thing I want to point out as well
in the red is that it creates a false identity in
us, right? So we start to
believe that it's better. We start
to believe that it's better off that we kill ourselves, right?
For those who are dealing with suicide thoughts because they have been receiving
these suicide thoughts and they. It's become so much a part
of their identity, right? When we allow thoughts
of lust to come into our minds, then we create
the false identity that we are,
you know, we are a person of lust, right?
And that goes both ways, by the way, both for heterosexual
and homosexuality, right? A homosexual that
says, you know, I was born with this. What they're really saying is I had
so many thoughts in my life that I have embraced that has become my
identity, right? So any sort of,
any sort of sin, any sort of false identity,
negative identity, non biblical identity, it is just simply
because we have received these thoughts over and over again and
we have learned to embrace those thoughts,
right? So from a biblical standpoint, nobody is born with homosexuality,
but they may have had trauma, they have, may have had,
you know, watched movies or
television shows over and over again until the thoughts start coming
into their mind, and then they embrace those thoughts and
it becomes their false identity. And then they justify that
by saying, I'm born with it. Right?
And the same thing for any other. Any other thought
of any other sorts of sins in our lives
that we embrace. Right. If I'm a compulsive
liar, then really I've just been
opening my mind to embrace the
temptations to lie. Right? And over time, I just allow
that to be. To form my false identity.
Okay, sorry, coming back to here.
Imaginations and fantasies, right?
I don't necessarily have to just receive thoughts
to then transition to imaginations and fantasies.
Movies help us cut straight to fantasies
and imaginations. That's really what the devil is trying to do.
If we get addicted to movies or we love to watch movies and we open
our minds to movies, then movies will start to imprint
on our minds, the imaginations and
shortcut us from having lots of negative thoughts
straight into imaginations and fantasies and then eventually into
that single act that then progresses to.
To a habit and addiction. Right.
Now, I. I've been sharing this at a school
before, in the afternoon, before I come into the evening to some
kids. And one of the kids asked a very interesting question today
in the sharing that I was given. She said, well,
if I have suicide thoughts and that translates into imagination into
the single act, then how am I going to develop a habit
out of it? That was an interesting question in
that I want to help you to understand that really
what are the single acts of suicide? How does it begin?
They start to cut themselves. And so the compulsion
comes to cut their arms.
And that really is as a result. So sometimes
a lot of the compulsions, as I am doing the counseling,
help me to understand possibly where the sources have
come from. And generally in kids, when I see them cutting themselves,
the compulsion is coming from horror movies.
And so they've been watching a lot of horror movies, and there is
a. The demons are coming straight into their hearts and
taking control. Right. Other times, other things that I've
seen is a lot of stress in the home.
As you know, parents are fighting, talk of divorce and
their young kids that the.
The demons will start to put it into their minds that it's their fault.
Especially if the parents are arguing over their kids,
right? Or the one parent starts to point at the
child and say, it's your fault because we're arguing.
Right? And then the demons will come and start to put it into their minds.
Right. So it is extremely damaging for
children when parents are having strife in the home and
even more damaging when they're talking about divorce.
And this is why the devil has attacked the
families, because it destroys the children and it
weakens their minds and then the demons are
able to come and start to wreak all sorts of havoc in
their lives. Right. And so if you are having children
that are leaving the church or are having children that are dealing with depression
or mental illness, a good place to start with searching
why this is happening is how has been your
relationship with your spouse. And that probably is
one of the sources or you know, the causes of
the things that the children are viewing. Negative thoughts.
Here's an example of a list of negative thoughts. I'm not going to go
into all of these again.
I'm thankful for the children because as I went through this list, they were examining
me on each of these points and what
it means. Now what I
think one of the things they called out was,
let's see, I'm not good enough
or I am good enough.
I think there's two here. I'm better than others.
Right. So that was. Or I am good enough. Right. So they were asking how
can it be a negative thought to be saying I'm not good enough and then
I am good enough. Well, what I mean by
this is the negative thought is when it's creating a
negative behavior or a negative feeling in
the heart. Right. So I'm not good enough. Of course, I think,
you know, we, we can connect with that. But I am good enough.
Meaning I don't need anybody else. I don't need God in my life.
Right. I'm fine. I don't need God. I'm. My life
is good enough. Right? Right. So that has, that's the
flip side of I'm not good enough. Right. I am self sufficient.
I don't need anybody else in my life. So two types of
characters will react in a I'm not good enough and
I'm going to jump into depression or another type of personality type.
And I've often found that those who could get
possessed are actually of a specific personality type.
And I'll try to come back to that later,
towards the end of the week. Okay. But there are certain types of
personality types that tend to gravitate into depression
or into being possessed.
Right. But the other personality type will react in a different
sort of way if the demons come and attack. And they will say, you know
what, I'm going to fight through this on my
own strength and I'M going to just push through this.
And I don't need God, right? And I am good
enough. And that's the flip side. And both are extremes
of where we really want to be, which is, Lord, I'm not good
enough, but I need. But Jesus is good enough, right?
Or I shouldn't. I shouldn't think that
I'm good enough. I need Jesus. So they both have
to gravitate towards the center, which is, I need Jesus in
my life. And if Jesus in my life, then I can live,
you know, I can live a perfect life in Christ.
Okay, so these are a list of types of negative thoughts.
Source of negative thoughts John 8. 44. Ye are of
your father, the devil, and the lusts of your father, ye will do.
He was a murderer from the beginning, and abode not in the truth,
because there is no truth in him. When he speaketh a lie, he speaketh
of his own, for he is a liar and father of it.
So the source of negative thoughts is, of course,
from Satan and the demons, and they're always going
to be lies trying to create a false sense
of identity. So all negative thoughts are lies of the devil.
Although it feels real, we need to learn to rebuke them.
And a lot of times, the reason why it takes so long
as I'm counseling with somebody, why it takes them so
long to get to the point of freedom, is because they're dealing with
all of these lies, and it has been so real
in their life. For example,
the girl that I was talking with you about yesterday, with the
crushing pain on her heart, that was real.
And so it's really hard to come
to terms with the fact that reality is
a lie, it's a false identity, and that I
can actually have victory through that. And I
liken it to the fact that, you know, this smokescreen that
the demons put in front of us is so real. I mean,
some of us feel it, right? Or others,
that thought is ingrained in their mind for so
long that it's hard to give up that false identity.
These lies that have been really becoming a reality
in their lives over decades. So negative thoughts are lies that become
our beliefs. And these beliefs over time form a false
identity. And we are miserable as a result
and have no hope in the promises of God.
So Jesus, what about Jesus? Did he deal with negative thoughts?
Did he have negative situations in his life?
Definitely, right? You know,
he was born to an unwed mother.
Is the perception that people thought, right, that Joseph
only married Mary because,
you know, she was with child and that's why
he married her. No biological
father that was not his father. Because, you know, she.
You know, nobody knows the origin. And so they. They talked
about him not really having that biological father. He experienced
living as a refugee in Egypt. He was tempted
in the desert. He struggled to surrender to the father's
will. And he felt alone and abandoned by those closest
to him. And he was betrayed by his friend and
sold for the price of a slave. So here
he could have been tempted into all of these
things, right? He was tempted to numb his pain. When his situation
seemed hopeless, he was offered the vinegar to
drink to dull his pain, and he refused that. He had difficulty
breathing. He cried out because he felt like God had
forsaken him. And so you can imagine the types of negative thoughts
that are going through Jesus mind as he's going through the Gethsemane
experience, as he's going through to the cross.
You know what kind of thoughts the devil was putting in his mind,
right? And then when Satan is tempting him, he comes to the wilderness
and he says, if you are right and causing
him to want to react,
retaliate, right? Because Jesus, by that time, he knows in his heart he
is the Son of God. But here comes Lucifer to say,
if you are the Son of God, meaning prove to me
that you're the Son of God. So Jesus dealt with spectacular,
amazing temptations that we will never understand what it feels
like, right? Because we're not God. All along,
Lucifer was trying to tempt him to use his own
divine power instead of relying on the Father.
For us, it's kind of easy to rely on the Father, to rely on God
because we have no divine power and we have no possibility of being able
to help ourselves out of our situations. And it's pretty obvious
once we continue in our life, but Jesus,
he had the option to use his divinity. And so
the greatest temptation of Jesus life was not to tap into his
divinity. Ellen White says when Jesus was on the cross,
all he needed to do was flick his eyelids
and legions of angels would have come and destroyed
everybody there, right? That was how close
he could have come to just ending it all for everyone there.
As he's on the cross and he's feeling that pain, he could not flick
his eyelids in the wrong way because if he did that with
a glance of his change of his expression,
the angels would have willingly come down and destroyed all of them.
That was the temptation that Jesus dealt with.
I want to show you some as I've been studying desire mages over the last
couple of years. God has revealed to me after
I've had that experience with spiritual warfare, God has just,
you know, opened my eyes to how Ellen White gives
us indications of spiritual warfare as we are going
through, as you go through the book, Desire of Ages. So I just want to
show you some quotes. This is about John the Baptist, and he's
in prison. And this is what Ellen White says. There were hours when
the whispering of demons tortured his spirit
and the shadow of a terrible fear crept over him.
So as John the Baptist was in prison,
a prophet of the Lord who was faithful,
the demons were still able to insert thoughts
into his mind. The whispering of demons.
Here's another one. Many among Christ's hearers who are dwellers
at Jerusalem and who are not ignorant of the plots
of the rulers against him, felt themselves drawn to him by
an irresistible power. The conviction pressed upon
them that he was the son of God. But Satan was ready
to suggest doubt, Right? And so we see here
in the crowd as they're listening to Jesus, they felt conviction.
But then suddenly thoughts came in of doubts about
who Jesus was. When the
Lord is about to do a work, Satan moves upon someone to object.
And this is talking about Martha, right? So when Jesus says, roll away
the stone, Martha says, but Lazarus has been dead for so
long, right? And this is the commentary that Eloi
gives. And then Jesus says, take ye the stone.
Take ye away the stone. Christ said, as far as possible,
prepare the way for my work. But Martha's positive and ambitious
nature asserted itself. She was unwilling that
the decomposing body should be brought to view, right?
So she objects. And then Ellen White says she objects because
Satan inserted the thought into her mind.
Speak up and object. Okay,
this is talking about the council of the Sanhedrin.
At this council council, Christ's enemies had been deeply
convicted. The Holy Spirit had impressed their minds,
but Satan strove to gain control of them.
He urged upon their notice the grievances they
had suffered on account of Christ. Right? And then
she goes into detail about all the thoughts she's putting into
their minds of the Sanhedrin as they are deliberating
what to do with Jesus, Satan takes control of their mind.
And you see, right at the very end, you can't really see it clearly,
but it says all this Satan now brought to their minds,
right? Helping us to understand all of us deal with
negative thoughts. It's whether you embrace them or whether you recognize
them for what's going on.
Sorry, I'm going to skip this slide.
Okay, so we're going to talk about open doors. Now, so we talked about negative
thoughts and I gave you some evidence of it again
in desire of ages. So what are open doors?
It says here In Adventist Hope 402, paragraph 1
and 2, Satan cannot enter the mind without our consent.
We should present before the people the fact that God has provided
that we shall not be tempted above what we are able to bear,
but that with every temptation he will make a way
of escape. If we live wholly for God, we shall
not allow the mind to indulge in selfish imaginations.
Or another way of saying that is negative thoughts.
If there is any way by which Satan can gain access to the
mind, he will sow his tares and cause them
to grow until they will yield an abundant harvest.
In no case can Satan obtain dominion over
the thoughts, words and actions unless we voluntarily
open the door and invite him to enter. He will then
come in and by catching away the good seed sown
in the heart, make of none effect the truth. So here's
where I get the term open doors. Okay, so demons
can take control of our lives. Demons can take control of our thoughts
and our bodies if we open the door, if we allow them
to come in. And we're going to look at different channels by which
they will come in. Okay, so open doors are legal
rights. So this is not a quote, this is just me explaining to you.
Open doors or legal rights are known sins that are not, that have
not been confessed or forsaken by the victim.
The devil is legalistic. And if we have opened up doors
into your life through sin, the devil will not leave unless the
legal right disappears, which only happens through confession,
forsaking and receiving God's forgiveness.
After helping people understand how demons attack us through
our thoughts, we should next have them share with us their background and
childhood. And through asking the Holy Spirit discover what
are the open doors in their lives. So this is the next step. If you're
doing counseling, right, and you've helped the individual to understand your
thoughts are not your thoughts. And so, and many times the thoughts that
you're having are coming from demons. Now we want to understand
how are they able to gain such strong access
into our lives, right? And that is through open doors,
then we need to lead them through a prayer of confession and renouncing
of their sins, claiming the truth that Jesus has overcome
every evil spirit.
So there are three main types of open doors.
The first one is what we call inherited curses or
generational sins. The second one is sins of the
flesh or vows or strongholds that we keep
Repeating to ourselves. And then the third one is occult
involvement or idol worship.
So we're going to go into detail into each of these three categories.
So as I'm doing counseling, as you're talking with
a friend, as they're sharing with you, you're praying that the
Holy Spirit will guide you to understand what
might be the possible open doors in the individual's life.
And you want to let them, you know, share openly.
Right. So you don't want to go, okay, let's talk now. Let me pull out
my list of open doors, and I will ask you a
question about each one. And you say yes or no. Right. It's not. It doesn't
work like that. You need to let them to speak freely
about their lives. Right. And as you're thinking about your life now,
and I ask as we go through the open doors, that you
reflect on your life. Okay. And I'm going to pause after each
section of the open doors for us to kind
of take a moment. And I'm going to pray together.
I'm going to allow you to pray individually to confess,
if God is impressing you, to confess at that very moment
about the open door that God has impressed you is
in your life. Right. And then I will close with a prayer. So we're going
to stop after each of these categories, and we're going to kneel together,
and I'm going to give you that time to confess. And after you
confess, I will close with a prayer and, you know,
we will command the demons to leave. Okay. So this is
going to be. We're going to work together on this.
Okay. All right. Let's talk about inherited curses
and generational sins.
Some parents and grandparents dedicate their children to a spirit.
So this is what happened, you know, with my wife. Her grandmother
was a witch, a witch doctor.
And because she had made that pact with the devil, the demons
laid claim to future generations.
Right. The sins of the fathers will be unto the third and the fourth generation.
And so she was able to see demons growing up. All of the.
All of her female cousins were able to see demons growing up.
And this was normality for them.
An evil spirit involved in an ancestor's life will often try to work
with the children when the ancestor dies. Sins of parents
can be weaknesses that evil spirits pressure the children
to commit. And this is where we get it from Exodus
20:5. Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I, the Lord thy God, am a jealous
God, visiting the iniquity of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them that hate me.
So any sort of generational sins that
we commit that can be passed on to future generations,
and the demons will continue to try
to trouble future generations. So in the Bible,
we have many examples of generational sins as
well. Abraham, he lied to his wife, and then Isaac lied
about his wife, and then Jacob lied to his father.
Jacob's sons lied to Jacob about Joseph being killed.
And Jacob's sons lie to a whole town of men
before killing them. Likewise, King David
committed sexual sin with Uriah's wife, Bathsheba,
and then Amnon, David's son,
raped his half sister, Tamar. Absalom slept with David's
concubines. Solomon had thousands of wives and concubines.
And then many innocent babies died in the fires of Moloch because of Solomon's
wives being pagan and promoting child sacrifice.
So the sins of the fathers will go into the
next generation. The next generation. The next generation. Right. Both from
a DNA perspective, but also from
the demons continuing to come after the children as
well. So if we want to break that cycle, we need to pray and
ask God to break the bondage that
has been kind of the demons have put upon the family,
and they're going after successive generations.
Okay? So a simple prayer would go like this.
If we find out that we have generational sins, and the
strongest one really is if you know that there's any witchcraft in the family for
fortune telling, any of that, or you know that
parents are having any sort of generational sins,
whether it be lying, adultery, or stealing
or drugs or any of these things, you want to pray that
God will break that bondage, that God will break
that stronghold that the enemy has over your family,
and that it ends in your generation because you don't want to pass
it to your future generations. Amen. We do not want
our children to have to suffer from the generational
sins that have been passed on to us. Right. And often when
I'm doing counseling with somebody, you know, when we're having
hatred with our parents or we're getting frustrated or angry
with how they're living their lives as we're
changing, I want you to remember generational
sins, which means that most likely, even though you
see it in them, they're a victim of their past generation.
And so we need to have empathy. We need to realize that
although the things they're doing may be hurting us
or maybe as children or even a spouse,
we have to look at them as a victim. Right.
And we need to Realize that the generation before and
the generation before is perpetuating this.
And you know, because they have grown up seeing it,
right? You know, they,
you know, girls who grow up in with sexual abuse,
although they are angry with what has happened to them,
they will grow up to then perpetuate it, or they
will grow up and go into prostitution, even though they hated the
fact that this has happened to them. By beholding,
we become changed, right? It's both a law for
good things, spiritual things, but it's also a law for negative
things, right? And so we need the power of Jesus to break
this pattern so that it doesn't pass on to future generations.
Okay? So I'm going to ask you to kneel with me now, and I'm
going to ask if the Holy Spirit has convicted your hearts,
that you need to confess this sin. You need to ask Jesus
to break this generational sin that's
in your family that you would have that silent prayer. So I'm
going to open with a short prayer and I'm going to give you a few
minutes to confess that sin.
And you may even read this silently if you want, as a template
and where it has that long line, you just put that
generational sin in there, okay? And then you confess that and
you ask Jesus to break that hold. And I will pray
at the end of it and will command the demons to leave. Okay?
So let's kneel together and we're going to pray this together.
Father in heaven, I pray for your Holy
Spirit to be with us now. I pray that your Holy Spirit will move
upon our hearts. And as we spend a few moments in
prayer individually, silently, I pray,
Father, that you will move upon our hearts the generational sins
that we need to confess or we need to surrender and
ask you to break those curses or break the stronghold of the enemy
over our lives. And so, Father, please send
your Holy Spirit to convict our hearts right now as we spend a
moment in silent prayer.
Father in heaven, I thank you for moving upon each of our hearts.
And Father, you have heard each of our prayers individually
and you desire to set us free. And because
we have confessed the sins before you personally
to you, you cover us with the blood of
Jesus. And I claim, First John 1:9, if we confess
our sins, you are faithful
and just to forgive us of our sins and to cleanse us of all unrighteousness.
And because you have cleaned us in the name of Jesus Christ,
Father, I pray that you would rebuke the evil spirits
that may have come in as a result of These generational sins or that have
been plaguing us have been surrounding us, have been
taking control of our minds and our bodies. And in the name
of Jesus Christ, evil spirits that have come in as a
result of generational sins, I command you in the name of
Jesus to go. The Lord rebuke thee, O Satan,
and you have no power over us. Our hearts belong to
Jesus. We have recommitted our hearts to him.
And Jesus is in our hearts and he will
set us free. Thank you Father for hearing our prayer.
For this we pray in Jesus name. Amen.
Okay, you may be seated.
So here's an important Bible text to memorize,
and it's part of a scripture song that we often sing.
2 Corinthians 10, 3, 6. For though we walk in the
flesh, we do not war after the flesh. For the weapons of our warfare are
not carnal, but mighty. Through God to the pulling down of
strongholds, casting down imaginations, and every high
thing that exalteth itself against the knowledge of God and bringing into captivity
every thought to the obedience of Christ and having in a
readiness to revenge all disobedience when
your obedience is fulfilled. So do remember
this Bible text and quote
it, especially the part where it says the pulling down of strongholds
and the casting down of imaginations and bringing into
captivity every thought to the obedience of Christ.
Okay, Sins of the flesh. Sure. Yeah, go ahead.
No worries.
Okay. Sins of the flesh.
Sins of the flesh. Here are some examples of
the sins of the flesh with the Bible verses with it. So we
have anger, envy, pride, gossip and criticism.
Bitterness, greed, rebellion, appetite and
lust. Strife, Unforgiveness. Use of
addictive drugs, also related to appetite or certain forms of
music and movies. All of these can
be sins of the flesh. Now,
the most powerful one that I see over and over again is
unforgiveness. Because it's really hard
to detect unforgiveness in your life because
it's such an invisible sin. And most of us don't act
out our unforgiveness, but we're just holding it in
and we don't respond. We may not outwardly
respond to it, but in the home or wherever we are,
we're going to act it out.
And it's sometimes something that we hold inside and
we don't share about it. It's one of those really powerful
invisible sins. And generally that's kind of
the go to one that is in my mind, especially when I'm
talking to somebody who's dealt with abuse or somebody who's
dealt with trauma their childhood. Unforgiveness generally
is the most powerful sin that is there.
And either it manifests itself as
unforgiveness for ourselves, or it manifests as unforgiveness
towards the person that's done
whatever they've done to us. Okay,
now I want to show you a bunch of.
Yesterday I told you that I went through the spirit of prophecy and searched for
names of demons, right? And so I'm going to quickly kind of go through.
We won't read all of it, but I want to show you all the demons
that Ellen White names throughout the spirit of prophecy.
Okay? So we have a demon of strife. And this is the only demon
named in Adventist home, okay? And it
says here, the demon of strife will be kept out of the family and.
And no separation of interest will take place. No alienation of affection
will be permitted if the law of God is obeyed.
Okay? So in every family there is a demon
of strife. And if we as a family are
doing our morning and evening worship together, if we
are praying, if the father, the priest of the home is praying for
his children, as Job did, then God would guard
the family, and the demon of strife will have less capability
to be able to attack. But what we have to understand is that in
every family, whenever a husband and wife argues,
it is not because of the husband and wife that they are arguing.
It is because of the demon of strife. And the sooner we pick
up on that, and maybe many of us have gone through our marriage for a
long time without realizing it. But you have to
understand, as soon as you start to argue, you have to notify
yourself or pray that God will give you the awareness that
the demon of strife is the one stirring everyone, okay?
And so we have to remember that demon of intemperance.
He can give us help to conquer even this terrible demon
of intemperance. So we have a demon of intemperance.
I will give you these slides so you don't have to take the
photo. Demon of appetite. There is a demon of appetite
that attacks all of us. And when you find that you cannot control
your appetite, there is most likely a demon of appetite there.
Or when you have addictions for drugs, for alcohol,
that is a demon of appetite. Demon of
selfishness,
describing Judas. If he would open his heart to Christ, divine grace would
banish the demon of selfishness. And even Judas might become a
subject of the kingdom of God.
Demon of greed,
demon of jealousy, talking about Saul.
Demon of jealousy, talking about Saul and his jealousy
of David. So every time he got taken over or possessed,
it was the demon of jealousy,
Demon of passion. Okay, so this is talking about
Saul. Still, this intelligence aroused the demon of passion
that had been slumbering in Saul's breast. So the demon
of jealousy led to the demon of passion or anger.
Demon of unkindness.
Some who profess to be servants of Christ have so long cherished
the demon of unkindness that they seem to love the unhallowed
element and to take pleasure in speaking words that displease
and irritate. So this could be a
bad habit of ours. Demon of evil and cruelty.
So talking about the effects of alcohol.
Demon of hysterics and satanic imagination imaginings.
Demon of ambition. For those
of us who really have our own ambitions and
where we want to be. We want to have a million bucks. We want to
become a millionaire or a billionaire. We want to have this car, that car,
how many houses? Demon of ambition.
Demon of heresy. False theology.
Those of us who are struggling with false theology and wanting to share
that the demon of heresy is behind that.
Demon of rebellion.
Demon of lust.
So as I said, demon of lust goes both ways. Whether it's
those who cannot control their desire for
premarital sex or those who are dealing with homosexuality.
Same demon. Demon of hatred.
Demon of pride, vanity, anger.
Here we have the demon of jealousy. This one
is an interesting one. Selfishness is a demon whose name is legion.
So selfishness has gathers
together a powerful legion of demons.
We have a tobacco demon.
We have a demon of wine.
Demon of appetite. We've talked about that already. Demon of
intemperance. Okay,
so let's
have a read of this. You know this counsel from Elamite,
it says, it has been clearly presented to me that God's people are to take
a fruit firm stand against meat eating. Would God for 30
years give his people the message that if they desire to have pure
blood and clear minds, they must give up the use of
flesh meat if he did not want them to heed this message? By the
use of flesh meats, the animal nature is strengthened and the spiritual
nature is weakened. So what is the purpose of flesh
meat in our time, especially the poisonous flesh meat that
we're all eating and also, by the way, the non
biblically prepared flesh meat. If you want to have flesh
meat and you want to have clean meat, please go to a kosher butcher.
If you take meat from anybody else, it is not biblically
prepared and therefore it is sin. So any
meat with blood still in it. So your juicy steaks any
meat with fat still on it. Kfc, chicken.
It is sin. We are not supposed to be eating meat in that way.
If you really want to have meat, please go and find a kosher butcher,
of which in Malaysia we can't find any because we're a Muslim country
and there are no Jews in our country.
But in this country, if you really want to eat clean meat,
please go and find a kosher butcher. Otherwise you are not eating
meat in the right way. But by the way, in this time and
age, if you are eating meat, it is weakening the spiritual
nature, thus preparing us to
fall into temptation a lot easier and
repeated. Falling into temptation then becomes addiction.
Addiction then becomes possession. All of it ends at possession.
Forgiveness. So as I said, unforgiveness is one of
the most powerful sins that
many people that I counsel with are holding onto.
And the true form of forgiveness, the prayer that we need to pray if
we want to have the forgiveness of Christ is what he prayed
on the cross. Luke 23, verse 34. Father, forgive them,
for they know not what they are doing, right?
Jesus gave us the model prayer for forgiveness, which is,
lord, I don't like what they did to me,
Lord, they have hurt me terribly. Lord, they have abused me.
But forgive them, because they did not know what they were doing.
They may have been an agent of Satan, they may have been doing wicked things,
they may have consciously done what they're doing,
but really they did not know that they were under the control of Satan,
right? They did not realize the depth to which they
were hurting us. Otherwise, quite possibly,
they would not have done it. So we cannot forgive
in our own strength. Christ depended on the Father's strength to forgive,
asked for the forgiveness of Christ, just like we ask
for the faith of Jesus. Forgiveness was so
important that Christ took time out from dying on the cross
to utter these words for our example. So no matter how
painful our situation, nothing will compare
with Christ's situation. So once we
utter the words, father, forgive them, for they know not what they do,
we will feel that relief, right? God will
give us that relief to our hearts. And even if we don't,
we ought to continue to pray it until we believe
it, until it becomes a part of us. Remember,
when we choose to take on the
thoughts of unforgiveness, then we are forming
that false identity of unforgiveness. You want to overcome that,
Then you need to start to pray the prayer of forgiveness until that
becomes your identity, until God makes
it our identity. And this is one of the most important Things
that generally when I'm doing counseling that we have to
come to terms with. Okay,
so again, I want to spend a bit of time now in
prayer. And I want to ask you to kneel with me
once again. If the Holy Spirit is convicting your hearts on
the open doors in your life, I'm going
to give you a little bit longer because sins of the flesh,
longer. List here. And if Holy Spirit is convicting your
heart of any of these sins of the flesh,
please confess it. And after you confess it,
I will close with prayer and we will ask God to rebuke
those demons and command them to leave us. Amen. All right,
let's kneel together and pray.
Father in Heaven, once again I want to thank you for
the blood of Jesus. And I thank you for his death
upon the cross, that he paid the price for all of our sins.
So if we choose to hang on to
the sins that we have committed,
it is our foolishness. It is to our detriment.
And so, Father, I'm praying at this very moment, if there are demons
that are surrounding us, that are hardening our hearts,
in the name of Jesus Christ, please, Father, bind those demons
and command them to leave so that we can feel the conviction
of youf Spirit. Father, we need you'd spirit to
convict us because many times we are living under
self deception and we're living under the lies
of the enemy. So please clear out those demons now. Send you'd holy
angels here to drive them away so that all
of us can feel the conviction of youf Holy Spirit.
Father, we submit this time into your hands. Please show us
the sins of the flesh that we ought to confess.
Father in heaven, I thank youk that
yout are a prayer answering God, and that yout have been hearing each one
of our prayers and it is yous desire to set
us free. Father, I thank youk for 1 John 4:18,
where youe've told us there is no fear in love, but perfect love casteth
out fear, because fear hath torment. And he that feareth
is not made perfect in love. And we
love him because he first loved us. Thank you, Father,
for first loving each one of us. And Lord, I thank
you that as we have confessed our sins, you have covered
us with the blood of Jesus, and you fill our hearts with your love and
your peace. And Father, once again
we claim 1 John 1:9. And we
thank you that you have forgiven us of our sins and cleansed us
of unrighteousness. And we thank you that you cover us with the blood of Jesus.
And because of that, in the name of Jesus Christ,
Father, we ask that you would command the demons
to leave our hearts,
to break the bondage of the enemy, to destroy
the strongholds in our hearts. And in the name of
Jesus Christ, I command any demons that have been
here as a result of the flesh sins of the flesh.
In the name of Jesus Christ, I command you to leave now and
you will no longer trouble us because we have confessed and
we are now covered by the blood of Jesus and he
has freed us from all of you in the name
of Jesus Christ. I thank you, Father, and we
pray all of these things in his name. Amen.
Okay, you may be seated. We're going to
take a short break. I hope as you've gone through this exercise
that you are feeling a little lighter.
As we confess our sins, Jesus is
freeing us from the burdens and the bondage
of the enemy. And you should feel the peace of God in your
hearts. You should feel lighter. And as
we take a short break, I pray that you will continue to ask
Jesus to speak to your hearts and all of our hearts
to convict us if there are any further
unconfessed sins in our lives or any open doors
that we may have not confessed yet. And we
will go into the last one, which is,
oh, sorry, there's vows and strongholds when we come back.
And then we will deal with the occult. Okay, so let's
take a short break, five minute break. And we'll come back
again at 7:40. Let's bow our heads for a short word
of prayer. Father in heaven, please be with us, refresh our
minds as we take a short break. Help us to be able to continue
to concentrate and be able to hear your voice as
we go through the rest of this seminar. For this we pray in Jesus name.
Amen.
Okay, let's bow our heads forward of prayer, shall we Father?
Once again, as we spend time to study this
topic of spiritual warfare, I pray for your holy angels to be
here. I pray that your Holy Spirit would move upon hearts.
And I pray that you'll drive out the enemy from here and
that they would not be able to disturb us. They would not be able to
interfere or deceive us. And I pray also for the equipment,
Lord, that you would sustain it and do not allow the
enemy to interfere there either. We submit this time into
your hands. For this we pray in Jesus name. Amen.
Okay, what are vows and strongholds?
Vows. Making a promise to do something, a commitment to
do something that can create a pattern of thinking that ends up controlling
us through our lives. Okay, so here are common vows
that I commonly hear from people that I counsel. I will
not let anyone get close to me or hurt me again.
I will use my anger to protect myself from being hurt.
In the case for my wife, it was I will use unforgiveness
as a wall of protection to protect myself
from being hurt. I'm alone and I will never trust anyone so
no one can hurt me. I will always be on guard against being
hurt again, being rejected again. I will
hurt others or take from others before they can hurt me or take me.
So any sort of like things that you just keep repeating to yourself over
and over and over again, that starts to define who
you are and especially in a negative way.
Conversely, we can repeat Bible texts that will
create an identity in us as well, right?
God is love. Or behold, what manner
of love is this? That we should be called the sons and
daughters of God. And so if we repeat that,
that becomes our identity. But often the
demons will put in our minds how they want us to be
right, and that will end up becoming our identity strongholds.
Kind of similar really, vows,
strongholds, but it's just a repeated pattern.
And this is more maybe actions here. So shutting down emotionally
when we're stressed or when we're frustrated,
withdrawing and isolating ourselves from people and preventing
them from helping us. Not wanting to open up
to anybody, reacting with anger anytime we have
little things happen that doesn't seem to go our way,
we're going to blow up. Blaming everyone else instead of owning
our part, Trying to control others around me,
turning to food for comfort. Right,
so bulimia or what's
the other one? Anorexia, right? Not eating food,
self pity and feeling sorry for ourselves. This can
be a pretty powerful one as well, especially for someone
who's dealt with abuse. You know, self pity
sometimes can be an open door. Trying to
please others, to gain acceptance or approval,
trying to rescue others and fix others instead of ourselves.
Instead of realizing that we have brokenness and we have problems that
we need to fix, we're just looking at everybody else. And this tends to
be a problem for those in ministry. By the way, not wanting to deal
with who the brokenness in our, you know,
our lives and wanting to go around to help everybody else
can be a way that we're trying to deflect the problem from
being able to heal. Getting lost in too much work. Video games,
pornography, Facebook, Instagram, social media. A lot of times
these addictions is not because I'm simply Addicted
to social media. There is broken in my brokenness in my life that's
driving me towards that. And I need to pray for wisdom, asking God,
what is it? What is it, Lord, that you
need me to deal with in my life? The brokenness,
taking from others, depending on others all the time, instead of being responsible
for my own life. So these are different strongholds
that the enemy with repeated negative thoughts can
put into our hearts and our minds.
We're going to move on to the occult stuff.
So I'm not going to pause here. We will combine
this with the occult side of things.
Okay, so occult involvement and idolatry.
This is kind of the third big area. And here's kind
of a list of things. This is by no means an
exhaustive list, but a kind of suggestion,
a suggestive list to you. Protective protection through amulets,
strings and tattoos or all sorts of other
things from all of our different cultures
could be an open door. So for my wife, that was
the rosary beads, that was one of the open doors for
her. But there are in other cultures,
especially in Southeast Asia, you can go and get these amulets or
these bracelets that will give you power or energy.
Those could be open doors, you know, the new
age crystals that have energy in there.
Meditation could be an open door.
And also there
are some of the things that we've seen for
tattoos. I'm not talking about just any tattoos. There are
places that will tattoo you that also will give you power
as well. So we had a Bible worker that we had to
do deliverance for, and he had over the course of his life,
flown to Thailand to see a tattoo
person who would kind of bless that tattoo and it
would give them power. And so we had to pray over each of those tattoos,
and he had to confess for getting those tattoos.
And then we rebuked and cast out the demon that came in as
a result of that tattoo. So it's kind of tattoos
that are blessed. But of course, also if you're tattooing on
yourself, cultic symbols, the all
seeing eye, you know, so a lot of the spots,
personalities nowadays, you can see, you know, they're tattooing
all sorts of things on their bodies. All Seeing Seeing Eye
or the Masonic symbols,
you know, that, you know, there's something going
on there as well. And so we need to be careful of those in
general, of course, don't do any tattoos. I was going to
ask, what is strings related with tattoos and amulets? Okay,
so in the Chinese culture, they believe that
if you go to bed and you tie a String on your toe, then the
spirits will reveal to you who is your wife.
So these are. That's. I put that in
there because, you know, in certain cultures they believe in
certain things like that.
Okay. In Thailand, they wear devil
strings. Okay, so there you go. Right. So it's
cultural. And I'm sure over here, the,
you know, American Indians, they would have their things as
well that they would be able to relate to idols and items connected to
idolatry. So if you came from a
different religion before coming into Christianity,
into the Adventist faith, and you had idols, then you
need to ask God to forgive you for worshiping
those idols. And you need to ask God to break any bonds
of demons that had come in. So for my mom, she was Buddhist before
she got baptized. When she was bullied at school,
she came home, she prayed to the ancestors and demons
came in as a result. Spirit houses and shrines,
this is common in places like Cambodia,
in Thailand, even in Malaysia. For the Buddhists,
outside the house, they will have a little house for the spirit to live in.
Worship of ancestors, fortune telling,
channeling and listening to mediums. If you've gone to get
your palm read, if you've gone to speak to the fortune tellers,
tarot cards, things like that, you are opening yourself up to
demon possession games involving spirits.
So Ouija boards, if you put your
finger and allow the demons to move it across letters,
you will get possessed as a result. That we had a girl who came
to us in our Bible school, school, I think this was in 2020,
and she had paranormal capabilities,
meaning after she played with the Ouija boards, she was
able to tell her friends an intuition that
she was having about what would happen to them and it would actually happen to
them. And so she was starting to be able to tell the future.
And that came in as a result of her playing with the Ouija boards.
And also she was dealing with a lot of unforgiveness in
her life as well. Books, movies,
especially those that are focused on spirits and witchcraft. And literally
almost every movie nowadays has an element of witchcraft
and spiritualism, meditation that
empties the mind and focuses on the spirits,
hypnosis. So anybody who's done hypnotherapy that
is not of God and you're going to have to confess
that, that and ask God to get rid of the demons that have come in,
possibly unbeknownst and not so obvious to you that have been taken
control, certain supposed methods
of healing. So in Philippines and some parts of
the world, it's very common for Adventists to bring their sick
children to see the witch doctor. Especially if they're not satisfied
with Western medicine, they will bring their little children over to
see the witch doctor. And we've had quite
a number of kids who have come to us who have been possessed since
young and have been dealing with demon possession as a result of
their parents bringing them to witch doctors to ask
for healing. And then there's a long list in Deuteronomy
4, 19:18, verse 10 to 12,
and Leviticus 26, 27, and also Revelation
21:8. Some of those are not just on
occult and idolatry, but also on sins
of the flesh as well. Yes. Question.
Can we have a mic? Sorry.
What about some of the. I guess you call them
alternative medicine,
like acupuncture.
Acupuncture. Acupuncture actually is
based on the philosophy that we have both yin and yang and
they're trying to balance our chi and the energy flowing through us.
So it is a. The philosophy is
wrong. So I would not be participating
in acupuncture. Any others that you caution
against besides acupuncture? You know,
Chinese medicine uses a lot of herbs and that's fine,
but the doctor that you may be going to may be
believing in qi and yin and yang
and balancing our hot and cold energies within our bodies.
So it's not so much the herbs themselves, but the
doctor that's administrating it and what his belief system
is. So you have to be careful of those as well. So generally,
a lot of the Eastern healing has
a different philosophy than what the Bible teaches us.
So you have to be careful of the doctor, not so
much the herbs, because you could use those herbs
in natural remedies, but the doctor administering
that may be having a different philosophy. So what about buying products
for companies that have that philosophy,
like have herbs that they're selling or what have you. But they
have that philosophy and they're. They're open. I mean, as long as you're not dealing
with them, you know, and those herbs are just
what they are, herbs with nothing else, and it's not blessed or anything,
then you should be fine. Yeah.
Any other questions on this? On the occult side of things?
So this ranges really wide. And one of the
big things that I've been dealing with in these
last few years is speaking in tongues as well.
So we get a lot of Pentecostals that come to us who are having harassment,
and generally when they confess this
ideology of speaking in tongues and the spirit that has been possessing
them when they have been speaking in tongues, they are free
from the harassment. So speaking in tongues is also
a big open door for the Pentecostals,
at least from our experience, as we've been helping those
who have come to us.
Any questions about the list? Anything that you've experienced
over here? One of the big ones,
another one that I've noticed that has been
talked about is this concept in the.
I think it's South American or American Indian.
I'm trying to think how to pronounce what the word is.
Ahasuerus or something like that. Have you guys heard of that? Anybody hear of that?
Sorry. Ayahuasca. Ayahuasca, yeah,
ayahuasca. So that's been. So this is where they all gather
together. They go out and I think they smoke a pipe or
they give you some sort of drug to induce
and then you kind of pass out. And when you wake up, you literally
see demons speaking to you about what you should do if
you want to be successful. And this is quite a big
thing that's kind of going around, especially those, those who
are talking about how to be rich, how to have success.
Some of them actually promote this in
New Age. Okay. Okay. Yeah. So there's been
some. Yes, of course,
Halloween for those who participate in that. We are putting ourselves
and our children especially on dangerous ground.
The demons are particularly powerful on that day because
the witches come out in force.
All witches come out and they are chanting and casting
spells and praying on that day for the neighborhoods that they
are in. Yes.
Sorry, could you use the mic? Thank you.
I'm a massage therapist and I have done
work on witches and others.
Now I always pray with my clients.
Is there any danger in that type
of hands on environment? No,
as long as the Lord is with you. Remember what happened to Balaam?
He was asked to curse God's people and he could not.
And in the end, what did he do? He tried to lead them into sin.
Right. And that opened the doors for their downfall.
So if you're dealing with witches, no matter what they
try on you, they're not going to, it's not going to work. As long as
you're protected and you are right with the Lord, you're walking
with the Lord. He will protect you. And if he doesn't want you to
go in, if he doesn't want you to do anything, if there's danger,
Holy Spirit will warn us and, you know,
tell us not to go in. Yeah. So no problem.
Yes. What if
you think you have a neighbor that may be practicing those Kinds of things.
Any suggestions in that regard? Pray for them.
Yeah, I've been doing that. Yeah. So as you pray for them and
you ask the Lord for an opening to be able to reach out to them,
the Lord will provide that opening. Yeah. So whatever
they're doing, it's. It's going to be nullified. They cannot do anything to you
as long as you're right with the Lord. Anything they try will be neutralized
as well. And God will give them the
realization that our God is more powerful
and they should consider changing allegiances.
What about within your own home?
Within your own home? Yes. Within your own home? Yeah.
It doesn't matter. Your children? Yeah,
it doesn't matter. Their choices. Sorry,
could you explain more? Is this to do with occult or not? Yeah, with the
occult. My son,
he's watching occult things on.
I mean, he's a grown man. He's 38 now. But because
of drug choices, he's coming out of a dark place.
Place. Right. And he
watches a lot of hypnotic
media things on his phone.
What? I mean, I'm praying for him.
Things are getting better. Over the three years that he's been with us,
it has improved tremendously.
The rages and the violence have declared
decreased tremendously. But he's
still addicted to this. I mean, it's something
on his phone and all I see is a screen with
some sort of. He's hearing it and I don't.
I don't know what it is, but I know it's not good.
Sure. Yeah. So look, that's. You can pray for
him, but ultimately it's his decision.
But you can pray that God will bind up the demons. So your go to
prayer for anybody that you're trying to reach, whether it's your own family,
your neighbor, your friend, your spouse,
whoever it is. You pray that God will bind up the demons so that Holy
Spirit can convict their hearts. Once Holy Spirit convicts their hearts,
conversion will come. Right. You don't have to try to argue
with them. You don't try to try to prove them wrong. The more you try,
the worse it gets sometimes. So the best thing is pray that
the holy. That the angels of God will drive
out the demons, that God himself will bind them up and neutralize their power
so that they can hear the conviction of the
spirit. That's what they need. That's what we all need. Right.
It's all what we all need when we want to overcome addiction
in our own lives as well, or any of our habitual sins or weaknesses.
So pray that God will Bind up the demons. Yes.
Could you use the mic? Thank you. The all seeing eye. I didn't realize,
but my daughter had a favorite artist in triangle with the all seeing eye
up there, and it was in her room and it was in our house.
It's not an issue now because everything's been destroyed, but this is
the sort of thing that certainly affected her.
Right? Yeah. So. And look, if you've
opened up your home to those things,
they will start to do things in the home, right. And you'll
start to hear things, you'll start to feel things.
You know, you may feel a presence. And so,
you know, you need to. We. You need to work on cleaning house.
Right. And so after this, I also, after the seminar, I also recommend,
go back to your homes, pray and ask the Lord if there is anything
in your home. And make sure you're praying and asking the Lord, because some people
can go a little crazy on this and start throwing out everything,
but, you know, you know, pray that the Holy Spirit will convict
your hearts and don't, don't go crazy with throwing out
things. But the Holy Spirit will tell you what it is. And if you
are feeling things in the home, then generally it means that
there are open doors. Can we pass the
mic over? Thank you.
Sorry. Thank you.
How about the. On the dollar bill?
Well, you can stop using money if you want. Always burning a hole in their
pockets. Yeah, you know, it's. I don't think, I don't
think any. Everyone has much choice on that one. And I
believe that, you know, God knows that we
all need to use money. And that's not, that's not going to be an open
door. But we're talking about, you know, tattoos or
some poster or some symbol of that. But again,
let the Lord convict your hearts, right. And so he
will show you what are the open doors that you need to
deal with in your homes, especially.
Okay. Any other question? Okay.
What about when you have a family member that's constantly watching movies,
etc. I mean,
I'm not the boss of them, so to speak. So what. What do you pray?
Everything is about prayer. But make sure you're not getting in
the way of the prayers. Right. Sometimes we feel like
we need to be the ones who tell them. And as soon as we open
up our mouths, we start World War iii. And then you
know that you are really blocking the work of the spirit. Right.
And again, make sure that you are dealing with the open doors in
your life because it may be that your prayer is not effective.
Right. It may be that God can't answer your prayers because
it's hitting the ceiling because of the open doors in your life.
Or it may be that the demons are getting you deflecting your
attention to look at everybody else around you
that is more obvious than you and you're missing out the open
doors in your life. And so we really need to ask God to search our
hearts and make sure that we are confessing
the sins that God is convicting our hearts of
and reconciliation, right? If God is working through
us and working in our lives, there will be reconciliation
in our families. And if you find that you are not having reconciliation
in the family, then it may be
that you need to focus on yourself,
right? And ask God to bring about that reconciliation.
And it may be if the other side doesn't want to do it,
then you need to pray harder that God will move upon their hearts,
bind up the demons, but give you wisdom to speak,
right? And to reconcile. So one of the also
most powerful ways that can prevent God from answering our
prayers is a lack
of reconciliation.
Let me give you a story. There is a story in
the Bible In Matthew chapter 17 and verse 14,
Matthew 17:14, When Jesus comes down
the mountain from the mount of Transfiguration.
He gets down at the bottom of the mountain, and then a father with
his demoniac son comes to him and he says,
jesus, help me, because I've been trying to get your disciples to
cast out the demons from my son. And they can't do it,
right? And the nine disciples are scratching their heads
because they tried casting out the demon. Nothing happened, right? Then Jesus
proceeds into a lesson to tell the Father first
that. That you have a lack of faith, right? And he says, if you pray.
And then the Father responds and says, I believe. Help thou, my unbelief.
And Ellen White says, if any of us pray that prayer,
we will never be lost, right? That is a really powerful
promise in connection with that prayer. I believe help
thou, my unbelief. If we pray that prayer constantly,
we can never be lost because we're giving God the permission
to change our faith, right? But then after that, he proceeds
on and he casts out the demon out of his son. And then
later, the disciples come to him and they say, jesus, why couldn't we
cast him out? And Jesus tells them, if you had the
faith of a mustard seed, you'd be able to move mountains.
And these things will only come out through
fasting and prayer. So a lot of people think because of that
story that the way to deal with Demons, when you're doing
a deliverance is you gotta fast and pray for the person,
right? But if you go to Ellen White and her commentary
on that story, she says that the reason why
they couldn't cast out the demons because of jealousy.
The nine disciples were jealous in their hearts and they were angry
and full of unforgiveness and hatred for the three disciples
who went, went up on the mount of Transfiguration. Jesus had chosen
the three and the nine were angry. And because of
their anger, because of their self pity, because if they are perceived
lack of justice or equality,
they started to have unforgiveness in their hearts,
right? And so really, and then if you look at when Jesus says, if you
had the faith of a Mustafi, you could move mountains, what is the
mountain in the story? Contextually speaking, there's only one mountain
there, right? Because I used to believe, oh, you know, if I
had a little bit of faith, I could tell, you know, the mountain to
move and it's going to move into the sea. That's not what Jesus is saying.
Jesus is saying, if you had a
little bit of faith, God would have removed the mountain of
jealousy from your heart, right? The mount of Transfiguration
represented jealousy for those nine disciples.
And they couldn't shake the thought. And every as they were
looking at the Mount of Transfiguration, they were getting angrier and angrier
and angrier, right? And a lot of us, we have the
wrong spirit when we want to help those that we think
need help. And we don't realize that there is a mountain of jealousy,
unforgiveness, and, you know,
reconciliation that needs to take place. And so when Jesus says,
these kind come out only by fasting and prayer,
what are they supposed to fast and pray for themselves?
They're not supposed to be fasting and praying for the other person,
the demoniac, right? Jesus did not need them to fast
and pray for the demoniac. Jesus needed them to fast and pray for themselves
that God would remove the mountain of unforgiveness in their hearts,
the mountain of unkindness
in their heart. Remember, there's a demon of unkindness, right? The amount of unkindness
in their hearts, the mountain of spiteful
words or words that do not convert.
They need to pray and fast for themselves before
they try to deal with the problems of the others, right? And often this
is the case in families, right. That we think,
okay, you know, I know the word, I know the truth,
I know what's wrong with them, and I know what I need to do to
fix them, and I tell them what I need to do to fix them.
But the demon of unkindness, or the demon of unkind words
or the demon of without
irreconcilable differences is
taking over the mind and it all comes
out wrong and it ends wrong. Right?
And so what we need to do is fast and pray that
God will change our hearts and fill our hearts with
so much love that without speaking,
God can move upon their hearts, remove the demons.
Conviction sets in. When they speak to us,
we can speak with kindness, right?
Often when you need to help somebody,
the most important words they need to hear is, I love you and
I accept you as you are and I'm praying for you.
That's really what they need to hear, right? Or I'm sorry,
right? And you know, in the church today,
there was a institution that was
set up or there was a. What's that word I'm trying
to look for?
Sabbath is a.
Okay, never mind. There. There is. You know,
communion was given to us to teach us reconciliation,
right? And today we have made communion a ceremony,
right? We treat communion like the Jews treated Passover
and the sacrifices. It had become an empty
ceremony, right? Why? Because Ellen White says we
should not go into communion unless
we have reconciled in the foot washing.
Right? But the problem is we do foot washing for
10, 15 minutes. How in the
world are you going to reconcile with
the people you need to reconcile with in your congregation
in 15 minutes, right?
And most of us, we're not going to have the time during the week to
do it either, right? And so as a church, we have
just made communion, you know,
a ceremony that we just get through,
but it was supposed to teach us once a quarter to reconcile
all our differences in the church so that by the time
you get to communion, many, many hours later,
at least that's the way that we do it in our church. You are having
a celebration because people who are sitting
on either side of the aisle who agree to disagree
have actually reconciled and they're sitting together and
there is love that's flowing through the heart, right?
A lot of the. The reason why a lot of our churches are not growing
are not, and God is not bringing people into the church to hear the truth
is because they might see the truth that there is
no love, right? And First John,
the book of First John deals with this, right? John says, the apostle
John says, if there is no love between a brother,
then Jesus is not abiding. Doesn't matter whether you come into church
on the Sabbath, it doesn't matter whether you are claiming
to know the mark of the beast. Doesn't matter whether you know Daniel
and Revelation. If there is no love in the church, that is,
there is no constant reconciliation
in the church, then there is no power because
there is no love. Right. And a lack of love
neutralizes. Right. So this is one of the clear
evidences that a lack of love, a lack
of unity amongst brethren,
neutralizes God's ability, not God's
ability, God's ability to
be able to help answer our prayers. Right.
God cannot answer the prayers of somebody who is not reconciled.
Right. And so as a church, we need to learn. We need to practice
the habit of saying sorry. We need to learn to say sorry more.
We do not say sorry enough.
Many just agree to live for decades in the same church,
just disagreeing with each other, just hating each
other, silently just speaking evil of each other from
the privacy of their homes and never coming together to deal
with reconciliation. So this is also one of
the most powerful blockages to answers a prayer that I have
seen. Right. So for those who are praying for others,
sometimes it is also that lack of reconciliation that we need
to practice. Right. Or the lack of forgiveness.
Okay, any other questions before we
go into prayer?
Yes. Can we pass the mic over?
It's over there. It's okay.
Okay, back to the Speak it in tongues.
Okay. How can it be in the Bible
and be a good thing and a bad thing? And how do
you know the difference? Sure. Okay, so there are six Bible texts.
So we're going off topic here. Kind of off topic,
but, you know, I'll answer it for you. There are
six Bible texts in the Bible that speak about speaking in tongues.
There are hundreds that speak about the Sabbath.
Right. And so to hang a doctrine on six Bible texts,
of which two are definitely against the
way it's being done in the Pentecostal Church today is dangerous territory.
Okay. So the way that we should study the Bible is that all
the Bible texts should align. Okay? So in
the Book of Acts, there are two instances of speaking in tongues.
One is at Pentecost. At Pentecost, Peter preaches
in his tongue Hebrew, and everybody hears him.
Right? So everybody who should not understand
Hebrew, Right? Meaning that it is an unknown tongue
to them, they suddenly understand. Does that
make sense? Yes. Okay. The next instance of it is when
Cornelius comes. Peter comes to meet Cornelius.
Cornelius and Peter speaks Hebrew.
Cornelius speaks Roman language. Neither of
them can understand each other. So at that moment,
they're given the gift of tongues. Both of them. Okay. And so
Peter now speaks in Hebrew, and he preaches the Gospel to Cornelius
and his family. And Cornelius hears it in the Roman language.
And then Cornelius speaks back to Peter, asking questions
as he's teaching, and Peter can hear him
in his Hebrew language. So both are given the gift
of tongues so that they can speak to one another. And the
purpose is for the conversion of Cornelius
and his family. The purpose of Peter being able to speak in tongues
is for the conversion of all that came for the Passover.
Now we go to the book of 1 Corinthians, and we have
speaking in an unknown tongue. Right?
Now, Corinth is a port,
and much like most of our cities today, the capital cities
of the world, all sorts of nationalities came
through the Church of Corinth. And so
you had people from all over the world in their ships coming
through. And what was happening in the Church of Corinth?
Because the letter to the Church of Corinth is about church
organization. And what is happening is people are getting on
stage and they are preaching in their
tongue, which is an unknown tongue to everybody
else in the congregation. Right? That's one way to look
at it. If I'm to line it up consistently with the Book of Acts,
then when they are talking about an unknown tongue in. In the
Book of First Corinthians, it is an unknown tongue to everybody
sitting in the congregation. So Paul is simply saying this.
If you are speaking Malay
or Chinese and you are being asked to do a spiritual
warfare seminar, and you get up and you speak to
everybody in Chinese language, it is an unknown tongue
to everybody. If you're going to do that, please get up
with an interpreter. But if you don't have an
interpreter, the only person that you are blessing and edifying
is yourself, right? Because I know what I
want to share, and it's blessing me, but it ain't blessing
any of you, so please don't do it. So in
that principle alone, the Pentecostals are doing
wrong, right? Because they're getting up on stage and they're blabbering
all sorts of unknown tongues, and Paul is saying, please don't
get up on stage and do that kind of thing, right? So on that
principle alone, they're wrong already. Even whether it's a
known tongue, unknown tongue, language of the angels,
whatever it is, they're breaking the principle of First
Corinthians already. Does that make sense? Yes. Okay,
so say, for instance, like it happened
to me when I was a child, My mom was very introverted and
shy and she didn't talk to anybody. She started speaking
in tongues. Pentecostal, sure. And her
brother was the same way. Quiet, introverted, didn't really
talk to anybody. Okay. He interpreted it a
few minutes later after she spoke it. Okay.
Yeah, that's very easy for me to explain that to you. Yes. Based on
the principle of how I've been helping the Pentecostals.
The demon that went into her to help her to speak tongues then went into
the brother and told him what she said. That's it.
Right, but according to the Bible,
that's not biblical. Right. According to the Bible, there's only
one way that the gift of tongues was given. Number one,
to preach the gospel in a land where nobody understands
what you're saying. And you've got to get the gospel message out.
Right. That's the reason and basis for the gift of
tongues in the first place. Secondly, if you're
going to speak in a tongue that nobody knows and you don't have the
gift of tongues at that time, please get somebody up here
to interpret for you. That's it. Right.
It's really simple about what the Bible is trying to talk about.
They're, you know, there's no added benefit in speaking in
the tongues of the language of angels here on earth,
Right. It would be beneficial for us up in heaven. But seriously,
nobody's getting converted by you speaking in the tongues of angels
if we just use our common sense, Right. So there's no benefit
for that whatsoever. And so the spirit that is coming out as a
result of the speaking in tongues in the Pentecostal churches, based on my
experience with deliverance, is demons.
Right? And so as a result, then they start to. As they get more and
more involved, and in this period of time now, maybe in
previous generations, they said, you know what, Speaking in tongues is enough. But now
they're stepping it up and they're starting to do a lot of harassment,
Right? And so a lot of them that have come to me, they're starting
to get harassed. There's things happening in their homes.
They're getting illnesses or,
you know, all sorts of torture. And so
as they. As I lead them through the confession of that and they surrender
that understanding of the gift of tongues, they get
freedom from the enemy. Does that
answer your question? Thank you. Okay, no worries. All right,
so let's take the time now, and if you have any further questions,
let us. I'll answer them individually after this. But once
again, I want to invite you to kneel with me. And if God
is impressing you if the Holy Spirit is impressing you to confess
any sort of occult involvement,
please spend that time to confess. And then we'll end with
prayer and we'll end the. End the meeting as well.
Strongholds as well. Yes, vows,
strongholds, occult stuff in your
life, you know, confess that if
you can whisper it out so that the
reason why I want you to whisper it out or move your mouth silently.
You don't have to be audible, but move it silently
so that the demons will hear it. Right. And that confession.
And then as we rebuke them and command them out, you know,
the demons will hear that you have confessed Jesus as
well. Okay. So when you're dealing with demons, it's important.
And when you're rebuking them, using Bible texts to rebuke them,
it's important to speak audibly because they can't read our
minds. Right. And so they need to hear that. Okay, let's pray.
Father in heaven, I thank youk for being with us as
we have looked at the topic of open doors this
evening. And Lord, as we've touched this topic of occult involvement,
I pray, Father, that your Holy Spirit, I thank you, that your
spirit has been convicting our hearts and bringing to our minds things
that we need to confess so that we can be free from
the bondage of the enemy, so that we can be free from their attacks.
And Father, I just pray at this very moment, may your Holy Spirit
give us the insight and also the courage
to, and the desire in our hearts to confess these sins
as we do it silently and individually now.
Father in heaven, I thank youk. I thank youk
for your Holy Spirit. I thank you for the power of
the blood of Jesus that covers our sins.
And I thank you for the healing that
you want to give to each one of us. And Father, as you have heard
the prayers of every individual here, I thank
you for the price that has been paid at the cross.
And I thank you, Lord, that as we have confessed,
you have forgiven us. And once again I claim
1st John 1:9. And I thank you for your
forgiveness. I thank you for the blood of Jesus that covers our
sins. And I thank you for the righteousness of Christ that now covers
us, that we are perfect in your sight.
And because we have confessed, Lord, I pray
that you would please remove the demons from our
hearts, close the doors so they no longer have access.
And in the name of Jesus Christ, I command evil spirits
that have been here as a result of occult involvement or idolatry.
The Lord rebuke thee, O Satan, And I command you
in the name of Jesus to leave. Thank you Father,
for the power of God and that your
love and your power is able
to save to the uttermost all who come to you.
And so Lord, we recommit our lives into your hands.
And I pray that you'll continue to work in our hearts. And I pray
Father, that you will fill us with the love of Jesus,
with his peace, with his joy,
and that you will help us to continue to
walk in the newness of life. And that you will give
us the power never to open those doors again. But Lord,
if we do, remind us that we should run to the
feet of Jesus. And as we confess immediately,
you will cleanse us and you will evict the demons. Once again,
thank you Father for hearing our prayer. Please bless our evening
and help us Lord to have safe journey home.
And I pray that you will please give us a good night's
rest. For this we pray in Jesus loving name. Amen.
Okay, thank you every everyone, and this concludes
our session for this evening. I would like to
invite you once again to come tomorrow evening.
We're going to go from 6:30 to 8:30pm
and we'll be here once again. So I'll see you again tomorrow
evening. God bless you and we'll see you tomorrow. Oh,
you have the topic. Tomorrow we're going
to look at how to have victory,
right? So what does it mean? Once we've confessed our open doors
and we've invited Jesus into our lives and we're
attacked once again, how can we have victory?
Right. What are the things, what are the tools and the weapons of
warfare that God has given to us that we
can use to go on the offensive against
the enemy? Right. And both in terms of helping somebody as
well as in terms of defending ourselves
as well. Right. So when those negative thoughts come, what do we need to
do? And we'll go in through that and we'll also look at how Jesus was
attacked. So we're going to look at the wilderness
experience that Jesus had and how the devil attacked him
and then how he defended himself. Right. How he was
able to rely on God to defend himself. So we'll break that
down as well.